<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 10:58:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robot Uan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/robot_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 10:58:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/robot_uan/</guid>
      <description>Design Considerations The purpose of designing and constructing this robot was to provide a generic test-bed for robot controller design and testing.Unlike most robot platforms used in education or research, UAN does not come with its proprietary development environment but uses Microsoft .NET Mobile edition, thus programming is done using the wide spread .NET framework from Microsoft.&#xA;The challenge addressed by UAN is that changing to a different robot or to a different platform does not necessarily mean a complete change in paradigm, and a substantial part of the knowledge and code can be transferred to the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Toolkit</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/robotics_toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 10:58:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/robotics_toolkit/</guid>
      <description>The high level design goal of this work is the creation of an autonomous robot navigation toolkit which is flexible, robust, easy to use and to configure and preferably independent of the sensors and actuators utilized. More information about the system can be found in this presentation.&#xA;The first component that is required is a physical robot. Although considerable testing and verification of the navigation algorithms used can be achieved through the use of a simulation tool, the only valid validation mechanism is an actual robot with real sensors and actuators.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
